Christopher Wallace

Executive Design + Leadership

A 20-year design industry veteran with experience working with tech and media powerhouses like Google, Microsoft, and Facebook. I'm a product design lead, an experienced manager of both design leaders and designers, and a builder able to translate ideas into real, working apps. My curiosity and innovative approach has been key in bootstrapping startups to meaningful revenue and successful exits.

portfolio <u>chriswallace.net</u>

email <u>chriswallace7@pm.me</u>

linkedin <u>linkedin.com/in/chriswallace2</u>

phone +1 972 837 7267

address 6400 Orchard Park Drive, McKinney, TX 75071

Work Experience

Lead Product Designer

Mar 2024 - Oct 2024

<u>Candy Digital</u> — McKinney, TX

Led product design efforts, redesigned website and marketplace, and created a design system. Created an interactive comic book reader app for digital DC Comics and other prototypes. Worked with cross-functional partners to ship new features and improve user experience across our ecosystem of apps.

Chief Design Officer

Apr 2021 - Mar 2024

<u>UltraDAO Studios</u> — McKinney, TX

Founded UltraDAO Studios, created Woodies digital avatars, and led a record crypto donation. Bootstrapped the company to \$2.6m revenue within six months. Released an acclaimed animated short and the first large-scale 3D avatars available on metaverse platforms.

VP Experience Design

Aug 2017 - Sep 2021

10up — McKinney, TX

Expanded design team, led projects for clients like Microsoft and Google, and directed the design team on California DMV's digital transformation. Mentored designers and ensured high-quality client projects.

Principal Creative Director

Dec 2009 - Aug 2017

Lift UX — McKinney, TX

Led design of award-winning, 2x Emmy-nominated digital experiences, including AMC Story Sync (The Walking Dead, Breaking Bad, and Mad Men). Partnered with clients like Frito-Lay and GoDaddy, and ran a WordPress theme business.

Front-End Developer

Aug 2007 - Dec 2009

Enterprise Rent-A-Car — Clayton, MO

Built website tools for booking rentals, ensured smooth design implementation, and maintained website functionality.

Senior E-Commerce Web Designer

May 2006 - Aug 2007

Network Solutions — Belleville, IL

Designed online shops for small businesses, collaborated on branding, and created store templates that matched client needs.

Education

Missouri State University

2004

Graphic Design

Saint Louis Christian College

2002 - 2004

General and Religious Studies

Technical Skills

Figma, design systems, design research, product design, mobile/iOS/Android, design engineering, Rive, Framer, Webflow, Storybook, CSS, Svelte, React, Next.js, Web3, blockchain, responsive design, accessibility

Awards

- Award: Best Environmental Initiative from an NFT project NFT NYC (2022)
- Nominee: Outstanding Creative Achievement in Interactive Media Social TV Experience, Mad Men: The Fan Cut — Emmy Awards (2015)
- Nominee: Outstanding Interactive Program, The Walking Dead Story Sync Emmy Awards (2013)
- Award: Best Second Screen App, The Walking Dead Story Sync Variety Awards (2012)